Contact

01017652324 (Mobile) ahmed1337saied@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ ahmedsaied1337 (LinkedIn) www.facebook.com/ Ahmed.Saied.45 (Personal) github.com/Phylake1337 (Portfolio) www.kaggle.com/phylake1337 (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Machine Learning
Deep Learning
Python (Programming Language)

Languages

Spanish (Elementary)
Arabic (Native or Bilingual)
English

Certifications

Convolutional Neural Networks
Machine Learning
Programming Languages, Part A
Data Structures | University of
California San Diego
Algorithms on Graphs | University of

Honors-Awards

California San Diego

2nd place E-JUST graduation project competition (Image processing track)

Ahmed Saied

Jr. Data Scientist @ Elmenus Alexandria

Summary

Passionate about coding, science, and computer vision. Avid learner. Research-oriented. Challenge seeker.

A machine learning engineer who is passionate about Al applications, especially in computer vision. I am experienced with computer vision projects such as detection, tracking and action recognition with tools like OpenCV, python, TensorFlow and Pytorch.

Experience

elmenus Jr. Data Scientist October 2021 - Present (3 months) Cairo, Egypt

Upwork

Machine Learning | Deep Learning Engineer April 2020 - October 2021 (1 year 7 months) Egypt

Rising Talent Five-star freelancer, Specialist in debugging, development, and integration of a Machine/Deep Learning module into an existing application, also develop an End-to-End Machine/Deep Learning-based application from the bottom up, achieving reliable performance, and accurate results.

Successfully Completed Tasks:

- Convert Multi-Class Classification code written in Tensorflow/Keras to its Pytorch version maintaining the same settings, hyperparameters, accuracy, and performance.

Client Feedback: "He was so awesome. Super willing to do extra work in order to get the job done. I think it's great when you get people who are curious to learn more and use their skills to do the best job possible. I will definitely work with him again!"

- Cleansed, merged, explored, and analyzed data for a Gaming Store using Python/Pandas/Matplotlib.

Client's Feedback: "Ahmed is a pleasure to work with, always bringing ideas to the project and very active with his communication. We've finished up work for the current projects but I'll definitely keep him as a contact for future projects that are a good fit."

- Debugged Python code with Pandas, and regular expressions to manipulate, and analyze a Data frame.

Client's Feedback: "He spoke English fluently and his python skills are extraordinary."

Evaluate new ML Optimizers in TF2/PyTorch vs. standard/common
 Optimizers Adam/AdaGrad on different types/sizes of Datasets eg:
 (ImageNet200, Cifer100, Flower102, StanfordCars192) using Python, Keras,
 Pandas, And Matplotlib for academic purpose.

iHub: Innovation Hub
ML Instructor at IJunior Program
July 2019 - September 2019 (3 months)
Egypt

Teaching Machine Learning concepts and techniques to 7~12 years old kids through 8 sessions under the supervision of iHub at the University of Alexandria, Faculty Of Engineering.

Alexandria University
Graduate Student
September 2018 - July 2019 (11 months)
Egypt

- A member of the graduation project team under the supervision of AvidBeam Tech. Egypt, And Alexandria bibliotheca technical support.
- The project won 2nd place in E-JUST graduation project competition (Image processing track).
- The main objective of the project is to utilize the Temporal Segmentation Network(TSN) to build an end-to-end surveillance system that is capable of recognizing human activities within the scope of its camera(s).
- Using the previously mentioned system to recognize actions in ONLINE mode, which means that a stream of frames is continuously sent to High-performance computer(HPC) servers to be processed, classified then the classification results are sent back to be viewed and examined onsite.

- Reimplement Temporal Segmentation Network(TSN) Algorithm to train, validate and test Inception CNN on UCF101 Dataset. (Also Kinetics Dataset used for transfer learning and performance enhancement).
- Implement the sliding window technique to enhance real-time performance.
- Tools: Python, Pytorch, Numpy.

Education

Alexandria University

Bachelor's degree, Electrical, Electronics and Communications

Engineering · (2014 - 2019)